Mark Gandolfo

\(+61 407 021 014 \)

@ mark@gandolfo.com.au

I'm a multi-disciplinary technologist. I am a Leader with 10+ years of experience bringing technology products to market as a Product Manager, Development & Delivery Manager, and a Technical Lead.

I am driven by the idea that there is a better way to identify business opportunities, to launch new products to market, to run technology-focused teams, and to build innovative software.

Areas of expertise include:

- Strategic product planning
- Workshops & stakeholder engagement
- Prioritisation & the art of saying no
- Product roadmap alignment
- Software development (interpreted & compiled languages)
- Customer interviews / user research
- Data analysis and analytics
- Team engagement
- P&L + Forecasting
- Go to market strategy
- Client relationships

Professional History

Hooroo - Qantas Hotels

May 2015 - Current

Product Manager

Hooroo is a Qantas Group company focused on delivering accommodation services to customers.

Hired as the third Product Manager when Hooroo was a small company of 20, I was brought on board to initially focus on short term EBIT growth, and later moved into core platform enablement (consumer payments, fraud, finance reporting, supplier payments) before finally moving into creation and operationalisation of the leisure strategy.

- Led multiple cross functional squads comprising UX, Developers and Marketing.
- Championed autonomy in the teams using OKRs ensuring strategic alignment with the company and providing regular updates to stakeholders to build and maintain confidence
- Identified key serviceability gap during customer research replayed research to leadership team and pitched investment in improvements to the post booking experience which resulted in usage by +3000 users per day, avg

- happiness 4.5 / 5, and \$150k in repeat bookings per week.
- Followed up on serviceability gap signoff with Design Sprint including customer success, developers, other product managers, account managers, and leadership to
- Identifying the highest value opportunities to be delivered by the team using collaborative workshops, customer interviews, industry research, and stakeholder engagement.
- Created strategy template which was adopted throughout the organisation to align the squads and product teams.
- Identified luxury hotels as being under-represented after competitive analysis resulting in the launch of 'Exclusive Qantas Hotels' resulting in \$1.6M per month in revenue, and the launch of a Qantas Packages product.
- Built and launched a set of (internally available) Public API's in order to provide merchandising and management of inventory to the wider Qantas Group, success was measured by usage, and ease of implementation.
- Launched a redesign of the search results page resulting in 7% uptick in bookings and 2% increase in time on page
- Set up analytics and business intelligence dashboards to measure new ideas, track the success of deployed features, and radiate information throughout the organisation.
- Stakeholder and vendor management across the Qantas machine including executive team, marketing in locations around the globe.

APN Digital 2010 – 2015

Product Manager (3 years), Development & Delivery Manager (2 years)APN Digital was AU/NZ focused, responsible for the digital publishing platform, online community hubs, event vertical, and multiple classified pillars (cars, property, jobs, general).

I was responsible for a team of 15 including Product, Development, UX, and Support. We managed readership growth and commercialisation of 47 digital news mastheads. Focus was on the development of core editorial and commercial products within a single bespoke CMS, in order to support the transition of readership from print to web.

- **Mentored and elevated my team** in product and UX practices such as Lean, Design Thinking, Design Sprints, Interviews and Synthesis to build better products
- Re-launched online classifieds connecting private and commercial sellers to buyers across multiple verticals (cars, jobs, general classifieds, properties).
- Re-launched Regional News Network user research driven re-launch of 47 news mastheads, leading to 35% increase in daily visitors
- Re-launched Finda social community an enhanced online news site without
 the legacy of the core mastheads, allowing for faster testing of new ideas which if
 proven are rolled back into the legacy brands.
- Introduced digital subscriptions and a paywall analysed data, built a commercial model around uptake and delivered a solution that saw 5% of users

purchase monthly subscriptions resulting in \$1.2M / month revenue

- Identified basic need for app based on customer research engaged a vendor, defined a solution and delivered resulting in 300K downloads in first quarter
- Increased high-value saleable advertising inventory by introducing a data management platform (Lotame) to segment customers, publish inventory via DSP/SSP, enabling off-network partnerships

Mocra 2009 – 2010

Senior Software Consultant

Mocra was a 10 person consultancy specialising in the development of web based applications.

Brought on as a software consultant, my role stretched the whole SDLC. Starting with problem identification with clients, solution design, delivery and iteration.

- Introduced sales pipeline in order to identify and nurture prospective clients through to repeat customers
- Implemented Scrum methodology to engage clients throughout the build process and organise our software projects

Avalon Property Group

2008 - 2009

Software Developer

Avalon Property Group is a franchised home builder operating within Australia

I was brought on to create an online sales portal for customers to customise their future home. This integrated with a large Windows based application that provided options and costs.

- Ruby, PHP, Javascript software engineer
- Developed deployment strategy using Capistrano reducing human error and deployment resources
- Developed architecture overview document describing target state for systems

APN Online 2007 – 2008

Technical Business Analyst

APN Online was a company focused on supporting APN Newspapers for the cultural shift from newspapers to online.

My role was to integrate legacy publishing and classified products to the new online database.

- Accredited as Scrum Master (Agile Scrum methodology certification)
- Integrated offline classified products online utilising a nightly batch process resulting in millions of classified ads being published per month
- Management of Jira and Confluence to centralise information across the organisation.

Other Interests

AussieV8.com.au 2004 – current

Owner

AussieV8 hosts a community of car enthusiasts, it utilises a pre packaged vBulletin software.

• 35,000+ registered users, 60k monthly unique users

- 400,000 pages served monthly
- Advert supported in partnership with an ad network focused on car related vertical
- Featured in Street Machine in "editors choice" section

Mentoring 2003 - current

Software + Product Management mentor (unpaid)

I donate my time as a mentor to junior and aspiring Product Managers as well as junior and graduate software developers in Javascript (React & Vue), Node, and Ruby

- A member of mentorloop & product-hive mentoring 2 product managers.
- Member of railsmentors.org since 2003 coaching over 15 students
- Mentored a pharmacist with no previous programming experience who was accepted into the <u>2018</u> Qantas graduate program focused on React + Ruby development
- Hospitality worker with no previous programming experience after 12 months
 of mentorship was accepted into the <u>2019 Thoughtworks graduate</u> program

Education & Various Courses

2020	Antler Launch Academy - 5 week workshop (part time)
2019	Conflict without casualties - 2 day workshop Nate Regier
2017	Insights for Innovation Ideo University
2016	Storytelling for business Udemy
2015	Introduction to Game Development Michigan State University (coursera)
2015	Software Product Management University of Alberta (coursera)
2014	Programming Mobile Applications University of Maryland (coursera)
2007	Scrum Master Accreditation - 5 day workshop Gabrielle Benefield - Scrum Alliance
2003-2006	Bachelor of Computer Science Latrobe University
2001	Diploma of Computer Systems & CCNA NMIT

Skills Matrix

1 = Notions; 3 = Average Proficiency; 5 = Expert

Business Intelligence & Data Strategy

Google Analytics / Google Tag Manager / Google Data Studio	5	10 Years
RJ Metrics / Magento Analytics	3	5 Years
Tableau	2	1 Year
Splunk	3	4 Years

ElasticSearch / Logstash	3	1 Year
Adobe Analytics	3	5 Years
Excel / Google Sheets	4 - 5	10 Years
Lotame (DMP)	4	2 Years
Adobe Audience Manager	3	1 Year

Operating Systems / Systems

Linux / Mac OSx	4	15 Years
Windows	3	8 Years
AWS	3	3 Years
Heroku	4	6 Years

Databases

Postgres	4	6 Years
MySQL	4	6 Years

Programming Languages

Ruby	4 - 5	8 Years
PHP	4	6 Years
Bash / Shell	4	4 Years
Java	3	4 Years
HTML5/CSS Sass	5	15 Years
Javascript	3 - 4	9 Years
Python	3	4 Years